Hello everyone, I am Sherry from MarvelousDesigner.
Today I will introduce some new features of MarvelousDesigner.
The first new feature is the GPU module.
Wait for a project file.
Here you can see two identical panels.
When you click on the panel, you can see that the particle diameter of the panel is relatively small.
The size of the panel is also relatively large.
Let's use a normal model to simulate the panel.
You can see that the simulation speed is relatively slow.
When the panel is relatively large and the particle diameter is relatively small, the computer operation speed will slow down.
In the menu bar, you can select different simulation settings.
There are four simulation properties.
In the new version, we added GPU simulation settings.
It is a simulation using the GPU of the computer to simulate.
It will improve our operation speed by relying on the graphics card configuration of our computer.
The second is the most commonly used normal simulation setting.
The simulation is used to make costumes animation.
The simulation speed is relatively high, so the computer operation speed will slow down.
The last one is the highest level simulation setting.
It can restore the most authentic use of the fabric.
Therefore, the simulation speed is the slowest.
I do not recommend everyone to use it.
The last one is the highest level simulation setting.
It can restore the most authentic use of the fabric.
If you use the GPU simulation setting, you will find that the sound speed is relatively slow.
Next, change the GPU simulation setting to simulate another version.
It takes some time to start the GPU simulation,
but we can see that the operation speed has been significantly increased.
At this time, the drag surface will be very smooth, and the response speed is very fast.
But we can see that the results of GPU and CPU simulation are different.
The CPU simulation is more stable, and the simulation effect is closer to the real surface, so it is suitable for making multi-layer clothing.
The GPU simulation speed is faster, but it is not stable. If you want to make multi-layer clothing, you need to pay attention to increase the thickness.
In the new version, we can directly rely on the symmetry of the real version.
Select a line and select the symmetry in the menu bar on the right.
The panel will be left and right symmetrical based on the selected line.
When you click on a point, the other side will also be changed.
When we create an internal shape, the other side will also create an internal shape in the corresponding position.
Adjusting the internal shape position, the other side will also operate simultaneously.
All this can be determined by double-chip.
Now let's create a set of symmetrical version.
As one can see, after we have created a body prefix in the two types of overlays, the body prefix will automatically be symmetrical.
If you need to cancel the symmetry relationship, you can select the middle version and click on the drop-down menu in the right-hand corner to remove the link.
If you adjust the version now, the other side will not be modified at the same time.
We have already set the symmetry relationship for some of the previous files.
You can merge them to make them into a whole symmetry editable version.
You can see that the merge section of the version has become a virtual line.
It looks like this.
In addition, we can also directly merge the linked version.
After merging the version, click on the right button to set the production effect in the menu bar.
After opening, the version will automatically be symmetrical.
You can choose a symmetrical axis at the bottom.
They all start from the corresponding axis.
If you choose the linear section, you can adjustid the pattern on roof.
Mr. Ray can analyze movement at both hands.
Thank you for your attention to the finished video.
Do not forget to like the video.
In addition, we can also zoom in when we create an internal shape.
Similarly, in the process of drawing, press the right button and the shape will automatically align.
In the new version, we added the layer tool.
There are these two tools in the 3D and 2D windows.
First, you can choose to create a layer tool and create a layer grid.
The mouse and mouse wheel version is displayed as a white version, and the other version is half transparent.
You can choose to create a layer in the 3D or 2D window.
After creating a layer, you can press the Shift and Ctrl keys to divide the grid.
If you need to divide the grid as a whole, you can choose the Edit Layer tool.
In the menu bar in the right-hand corner, select All Dividing.
Press Ctrl and Shift and hold down the left mouse button to extend the layer.
The layer can be adjusted as needed.
After selecting two points, you can merge these two points.
If you need to merge two topos, you can select the topo tool and then select all merge in the output menu.
In the upper right corner of the 3D window, you can see the merge window.
Here we can set a length.
If the distance between the two topos is less than the value, they will be merged.
If the merge points are too many, you can adjust them according to your needs.
Adjust the value to merge the topos.
In the process of creating a topo, you need to pay attention that if there is a overlap, you need to place the mouse on the topo that you want to create.
Therefore, the 2D window will be more convenient to create a merge topo.
You can directly select the topo on the pocket topo.
Then you can refer to the output menu.
Then you can refer to the output menu and create a topo on the inner layer.
After creating a topo, you can select reset grid.
You can see that there are two kinds of reset grid types, colon and replacement.
When you select the replacement,
Reboot will replace the original version.
If you choose Reboot, the new version will be replaced by Reboot.
In the new version, we added a clothing display style that can display the surface of the clothing line frame.
We can see that the grid formed from the original version is the same as when we took it out.
Next, I would like to introduce our new function, grid separation.
We can see that the grid of the rectangular version is relatively large.
The grid refers to the distance between the top and bottom of the grid.
In the new version, we have newly added the tool to select the grid using brush.
After selecting, the 3D window in the upper right corner can set the size of the brush.
After selecting a region, we can separate it.
We can see that the grid in this region is significantly larger and the grid is smaller.
We can change the name of the separation and the level of separation in the attribute editor in the upper right corner.
The higher the level of separation, the more the grid, the smaller the grid.
If the level of separation is set to 0, the separation effect will not exist.
Or you can directly select the separation area and delete the separation.
This is a brief introduction to the grid separation function.
Next, let's see how to apply it to our clothing.
Now we have a template.
After opening the simulation, we will find that the simulation speed is very fast, but the fold is not delicate enough.
After reducing the particle diameter, the number of grid will increase and the operation speed will decrease, but the fold will be more delicate.
We can see that the grid has been separated.
Like this, when we need some details, we can see the grid separation.
First, use the brush tool to select the grid to be separated.
After selecting the grid, we can do the separation and start the simulation.
We can see that the fold of the details will be retained.
The overall fold shape is also similar.
We can select whether to display grid separation in the 3D window.
In addition, there are two optimization options.
First, we can select the grid to be separated.
The first is the environment setting in the 3D window.
We can adjust it directly.
We can choose to display the light controller.
In the light controller, we can set the light intensity and angle of the Marvellous Designer.
Then the wind controller can be activated to simulate the wind blowing effect.
We can also select whether to display the shadow and 3D grid.
Another advantage is that we will integrate the drawing sheet and the internal drawing tool.
Long press can select the individual tool.